Guide to the Emilio Q. Daddario Congressional Papers, 1959 - 1970
Emilio Q. Daddario Congressional Papers, 1959 - 1970
- Series 3: Audio-Visual File, 1959-1970
  About 100 telecasts to his Connecticut constituents from WTIC-TV Hartford, WHNB-TV New Britain, and WNHC-TV New Haven. These are entitled Your Congressman from Connecticut. These are dated but not marked as to subject.
  Special items include film of Daddario with President Johnson (about 2 minutes); a V.I.P. Tour in South Vietnam with shots of Daddario and other congressmen dated November 20, 1965 from the Army Pictorial Center.
  Ten audio tape recordings include Congressional reports, a Daddario address on patents to the Chamber of Commerce, May 21, 1961; his address delivered to the Interparliamentary Union Conference in Tehran, Iran, October 1, 1966 (broadcast over Voice of America); and his Trumbull Lecture, The Crucial Half-Century for Science and Society, to the Yale Science and Society Forum, Yale University, November 17, 1969.
  - Tape recordings, television tapes, and motion pictures concerning Daddario's service as a member of the U.S. House of Representatives, 1959-1970 (Box 15-17)
- Series 4: Campaign File, 1960-1970
  Papers pertaining to Daddario's campaigns for re-election to the U.S. House of Representatives in 1960, 1962, 1964, 1966, and 1968 and his campaign for Governor of Connecticut in 1970. As these materials come solely from the Congressman's Washington office, this is not the kind of full file that developed in his headquarters in the state.
  - Henry Jackson (Sen.-D-Washington) packet on campaigning, 1960 (Box 18)
  - Town chairmen listing, 1960-1962 campaigns
  - Speeches campaign, 1962
  - Thank you letters to campaign contributors, 1962
  - 1962 reader campaign file
  - 1962 campaign labor file
  - 1962 campaign issue (medical care for the aged)
  - 1962 campaign press releases
  - 1962 Congressional convention
  - 1962 Congressional campaign correspondence
  - 1962 campaign photos
  - 1962 congratulations on victory
  - 1962 newspaper clippings
  - 1962 miscellaneous campaign file
  - Connecticut Public Affairs Report, 1964 election
  - Campaign 1964, correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings
  - 1964 campaign reader file
  - Campaign 1964 - appointments to committees (Box 19)
  - 1964 newspaper clippings
  - Campaign 1964 - bills and invoices
  - 1963 house voting record
  - Brochures - 1964 campaign
  - Campaign 1964 press releases
  - Radio-TV programs, 1964 campaign
  - Editorial endorsements - thank you notes
  - 1964 Campaign - labor files, photos, clippings
  - 1964 Campaign - General Correspondence
  - 1964 Campaign Miscellaneous file
  - 1966 Campaign Israel file
  - Congressional Convention, 1966
  - Democratic Women's Campaign Convention, 1966
  - Democratic National Committee, 1967-1969
  - Democratic Study Group, 1967-1969
  - Campaign 1968 - Miscellaneous file
  - Democratic National Convention Committee, 1968-1969
  - 1968 Campaign press clippings
  - 1968 Israel file
  - Inauguration 1969
  - Campaign 1970 correspondence
  - 1970 campaign press clippings
- Series 5: Connecticut and Constituency File, 1959-1970
  Communications pertaining to matters as varied as the plight of the New Haven Railroad and individual social security and immigration claims. The topics are enormously varied and correspondence illustrates how Daddario dealt with the very complex as well as some quite humble demands. The correspondents are chiefly from his own district and the topics mostly confined to Connecticut.
  - Town Files (Box 20)
    - Bloomfield, 1965-1970
    - East Hartford, 1966-1970
    - East Windsor, 1959-1968
    - Glastonbury, 1964-1967
    - Glastonbury, 1968-1970
    - Hartford, 1967
    - Hartford, 1968
    - Hartford, 1969
    - Hartford, 1970
    - Manchester, 1966-1968
    - Manchester, 1968-1970
    - Marlborough, 1965
    - Middletown, 1960-1966
    - Middletown, 1969
    - New Britain, 1964
    - New Britain, 1966-1968
    - New London, 1964-1966
    - Newington, 1959-1967
    - Newington, 1968-1970
    - Norwich, 1962
    - Out of District Towns, 1966-1968
    - Out of District Towns,1969-1970
    - Rocky Hill, 1964-1966
    - Rocky Hill, 1968-1970
    - South Windsor, 1964-1967
    - South Windsor, 1968-1970
    - Wapping, 1969
    - West Hartford, 1959-1967
    - West Hartford, 1968-1970
    - Wethersfield, 1965-1970
    - Windsor, 1964-1966
    - Windsor, 1968-1970
    - Windsor Locks, 1964-1968
  - Alphabetical Files (Box 21)
    - Air pollution study, New Haven, Conn., June 1968
    - Connecticut Army Reserve, 1970
    - Brookhaven National Laboratories, 1965-1966
    - Connecticut Census, 1960-1970
    - Hartford Census Tracts, 1960
    - Central Connecticut Communities, Cultural, Civic and Charitable Corporation, 1965-1966
    - Connecticut Constitutional Convention, 1965
    - Connecticut General Assembly, 1967-1969
    - Connecticut Interregional Planning Program (6 vol. set)
    - Connecticut Patent Law Association Meeting, 1968
    - Connecticut Public Health Association 50th Anniversary Meeting, December 2, 1966
    - Connecticut River (primarily area recreational bill), 1964-1967
    - Connecticut State file, 1966
    - Connecticut State file, 1967
    - Connecticut State file, 1968
    - Connecticut State file, 1969
    - Connecticut State file, 1970
    - Connecticut, University of, 1963-1969 (Box 22)
    - Dempsey, John N., Governor of Connecticut
    - Downey, John, New Britain man, prisoner of war in China
    - Economic trends in Connecticut
    - (Connecticut) Educational Policy, disabled children, 1969
    - Educational Progress Plan, Hartford '74, 1969
    - Environmental Science Proposal, University of Connecticut, 1968-1969
    - Export Origin Study - U.S. Department of Commerce, Connecticut 1st Congressional District, 1962
    - (Connecticut) General Flight Forum, May 15, 1963
    - Flood control (including Park River Trout Brook), 1959-1970
    - Hartford, University of, 1961, 1967
    - Highways (including I-291 West Hartford) - Boston -Washington Highway System Study, 1964
    - Industrial Site Brochure, Middletown
    - (Connecticut) Industries, 1965-1966
    - Land Grant Colleges, 1966
    - Machiasport, Maine Project (harbor for oil tankers)
    - (Connecticut) Medical Insurance (Aged), 1961
    - Medical Schools (University of Connecticut, 1966-1970, Yale 1964-1967)
    - (Connecticut) National Guard, 1961-1965
    - Greater Hartford Negro Community, 1967
    - New England file, 1965-1968
    - New England file, 1969-1970
    - Officials of the State of Connecticut, 1967 list
    - People-to-People Conference, Hartford, 1959-1964
    - (Connecticut) Anti-Poverty Program, 1966-1968
    - Railroads (Box 23)
      - 1967 mergers, financial reports
      - New Haven railroads
        2 folders of correspondence.
      - I.C.C. financial report on the Penn Central, 1970
      - New Haven railroad, miscellaneous file
      - Articles of the New Haven Railroad
      - Report on operations of New York, New Haven, and Hartford railroad company, August 12, 1965
      - Railroad merger information, 1965
      - Railroad loan guaranty
      - New York, New Haven, Hartford Company abandonment of certain lines and runs
      - Commuter turbine motor trains, 1965 report
      - Tri-State Transportation Commission, 1963, 1965 reports
    - (Connecticut) Redistricting, 1964-1966
    - Regional Dissemination Center for New England, November 15, 1966: NASA feasibility study
    - Technical services program of Connecticut, 1966 (Box 24)
    - Town Meeting for Tomorrow, Hartford, November 19-21, 1964
      Includes report to delegates, 1965.
    - Southwestern (Connecticut) Management Council
    - United Aircraft, East Hartford, 1965-1967
    - United States Government
      - Agency Programs in Connecticut
      - Area Redevelopment Administration
      - Bureau of Public Roads
      - Office of Civil Defense
      - Federal-aid Airport Program
      - General Services Administration
      - Housing and Home Financing Agency
      - Miscellaneous (fisheries, wildlife, atomic energy)
      - National Guard Bureau
      - Small Business Administration
      - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
      - Veterans Administration
      - Department Programs in Connecticut
        - Department of Agriculture
        - Department of Defense
        - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare
        - Department of the Interior
        - Post Office Department
        - State Department
    - Veterans Hospital, newington, 1966-1968
    - Visitors file, 1969
    - Voting record of the House Republican Member from Connecticut, 1962
    - Water resources
      - Colebrook River Dam, 1961-1969
      - Connecticut Projects, 1964-1969
      - Farmington River Valley, 1963, 1967
      - Legislation, 1966-1970
      - Pollution in Bantam Lake, 1970
      - Northeast Compact, 1961-1963
      - Saline water (desalination projects), 1960, 1967
- Series 6: Legislative File, 1959-1970
  Bills introduced by Daddario and other bills, hearings, committee reports and floor action on legislation in the 86th, 87th, 88th, 89th, 90th, and 91st Congresses. Correspondence about legislation is filled with printed material. The organization of this file is both by subject and by chronology, not consistently one or the other.
  - Agriculture, Department of (General), 1968-1970 (Box 25)
  - Agriculture: Mini farmers' quotas for importation, 1967-1970
    2 folders.
  - Air Pollution, General, 1968-1970
  - (Proposed) Air Quality Act of 1970, speech
  - Appropriations Measures, General, 1969-1970
  - Atomic Energy, 1967-1969
  - Aviation, General, 1968-1970
    S.S.T., 1969-1970
  - Banking and Currency, 1969-1970
  - Bills, co-sponsored, 1960-1970
  - Bills, co-sponsored, dead, 1970
  - Bills, introduced by Daddario, 1960-1970
  - Bills, introduced by Daddario, 1960-1970 (Box 26)
  - Civil Rights, 1968-1970
  - Civil Service, Bill to amend Civil Service Retirement System, 1969-1970
  - Civil Service, General, 1969-1970
  - District of Columbia, 1968-1970
  - Education, Federal Aid to, 1968-1970
  - Education, General, 1969-1970
  - Equal Rights, 1969-1970
  - Fair trade, bills, and laws, 1967-1970
  - Foreign Affairs
    - Bills and laws, 1968-1969
    - Communism in the U.S., 1968-1970
    - General, 1967
    - General, 1968-1970
    - Israel (war), 1967
    - Laos, 1969-1970
    - Middle East, 1967-1969
    - Vietnam Civil Action Program, 1968
    - Vietnam, General, 1967
    - Vietnam, General, 1969-1970
  - Foreign aid, 1967
  - Harvard Journal on Legislation, article, 1970
  - Health, Drugs, 1969-1970 (Box 27)
  - Health and Medical, General, 1969-1970
  - Mental Health, General, 1968-1970
  - Highways, Beautification, 1968
  - Highways, General, 1969-1970
  - Housing, General, 1968
  - Hunger in America, 1969-1970
  - Immigration, General, 1968-1970
  - Insurance, 1968-1969
  - Intelligence, Bills and laws, C.I.A., 1963-1965
  - Intelligence, General articles, clippings, 1960-1967
  - Joint Committee on the Intelligence Community, 1961-1963
  - Kennedy, John F., 1968-1970
  - Farm Labor, General, 1968-1970
  - Labor, General, 1967
  - Labor, General, 1969-1970
  - Military, bills and laws, 1968-1970
  - Military, General, 1968-1970
  - Military, Selective Service
  - Military legislation A. B. M., 1969-1970
  - Miscellaneous files
    - Animals (Box 28)
    - Congress
    - Copyright law, March 18, 1968
    - Election '68
    - Electoral College (Vote 18), 1968-1969
    - Firearms, 1968-1970
    - General, 1969-1970
    - Juvenile Delinquency, 1969-1970
    - National Holidays, 1968-1970
    - National Timber Supply, 1969
    - Nationalities, 1968-1970
    - Obscenity, 1969-1970
    - Oil, 1969-1970
    - Parks and Recreation, 1968
    - Power, 1968-1970
    - Radio-TV, 1968-1970
    - Riots, college disorders, 1968-1970
    - Small businesses, 1967-1970
  - Miscellaneous Supreme Court (Douglas Impeachment, school prayer) (Box 29)
  - National Foundation on Arts & Humanities, 1968-1970
  - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1968-1970
  - Post Office, Bills and Laws, 1969-1970
  - Post Office, General legislation, 1967
  - Post Office, General legislation, 1969-1970
  - Post Office, Special Stamps, 1966-1970
  - Power - National resources, 1963-1970
  - Social Security, bills and laws, 1965-1969
  - Social Security, General, 1967
  - Social Security, General, 1969-1970
  - Social Security, Inclusion on Medicare, Chiropractic Services, 1969-1970
  - Taxation, bills and laws, 1968-1970
  - Taxation, General, 1967
  - Taxation, General, 1967 (Box 30)
  - Taxation, General, 1969-1970
  - Taxation, Interstate, 1967
  - Tax reform legislation, 1963
  - Taxation, single persons
  - Tax-sharing
  - Taxation, 10 percent surcharge
  - Trade, 1969-1970
  - Transportation, General, 1969-1970
  - Veterans, bills and laws, 1968-1970
  - Veterans, General, 1970
  - Voting records, 88th-90th Congress
  - Water pollution, legislation, 1962-1970
    Muskie letter.
  - Ways and Means, General
  - Welfare Legislation, General, 1970
- Series 7: Science and Aeronautics Policy, 1959-1970
  Varied materials about the two most important committees Daddario served on. One was Science, Research and Development and the other was Patents.
  - Aircraft (Box 31)
    - Lockheed Aircraft - Sub-contractor survey
    - Paris Air Show, 1963
    - Supersonic Aircraft
      - Supersonic Aircraft, 1963
      - Committee File, Management Advisory Panel, June 1964
      - SST and other Aeronautical Exploration, 1965
      - Panel on Science and Technology, January 1965
  - Anti-Ballistic Missile System (ABM)
    - Varo Mfg. Co., Inc. - 1960 - marked secret
    - Varo Mfg. Co., Coherent focused radiation, 1960
    - Articles, correspondence, statements, 1968-1969
    - Clippings, speeches, etc. on ABM, 1969
  - Atomic Energy
    - Testimony of Commissioner Gerald F. Tape, May 7, 1964
    - Nuclear War - Congressional Record, March 28, 1968
    - Shoreham Nuclear Power Station, 1970
  - Birth Control
    - Science Subcommittee - Birth Control, 1965
    - Science Committee - Birth Control, 1965
  - Earthquakes
    - Earthquake prediction, September 1965
  - Environmental Problems
    - Science and Astronautics Committee, Environmental Sciences, 1965
    - Pollution Bills, 1965
    - Water Resources Research, 1965
    - Panel Meeting, August 23, 1965
    - Air Pollution, 1965-1967
    - Water Pollution articles, 1966-1968
    - Subcommittee report on pollution, 1966
    - Environmental Sciences, 1966
    - Pollution, 1966
    - Speech to National Conference on Air Pollution, December 13, 1966
    - Environmental Medicine and Instrument Technology, 1967
    - Environmental Quality Hearings, 1967
    - Correspondence with Dr. William Shockley, 1967-1969
    - Articles by Athelstan Spilhaus, 1967-1969
    - Muskie Hearings, January 1968 (Box 32)
    - Congressional Record, February 29, 1968 - speech on crisis in Hartford
    - Pollution, 1968
    - Tenth Meeting of Panel on Science and Technology, February 4-6, 1969
      Includes speech by John Gardner, articles and paper by C. A. Doxiadis.
    - Draft of report on environmental programs at universities, September 1969
    - Environmental Quality, 1969-1970
    - Specimen pages from Ehrlich book, 1970
    - United Nations Conference on the Human Environment, 1972
  - Fire Safety
    - Statements on Fire Research and Safety Act of 1967
    - Fire Research and Safety, 1967-1968
    - Fire Research and Safety, 1969-1970
  - Institutional Grants Bill
    - Miller Bill, 1967
    - National Foundation for the ARts and Humanities, National Endowment for the Humanities, 1969
    - Estimates of Institutional Grants, 1969
    - Institutional Grants, 1969
    - Institutional Grants Back-Up Data, Testimony, Notes, 1969
  - International Biological Program (IBP) (Box 33)
    - International Biological Program, 1967-1969
    - Correspondence with IBP, January 1969-May 1969
    - International Biological Program, September 1969
  - Life Sciences
    - Biosciences Report, January 1961
    - Life Sciences draft and press release, 1961
    - Life Science Inter-Agency Coordination, 1963
    - NASA Computer functions, 1964
    - Life Sciences, General correspondence, 1966
  - National Academy of Sciences
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1964-1965
    - Science and Astronautics Committee Meeting with National Academy of Sciences, April 26, 1965
    - Division of Mathematical Sciences Annual Report, 1969
    - National Academy of Sciences News Report, 1968-1970
  - National Science Foundation (NSF)
    - Haworth Testimony, October 29, 1963
    - NSF Draft, 1965
    - Testimonial Dinner, May 27, 1965
    - NSF Article in Christian Science Monitor, April 30, 1966
    - NSF, 1968 (two folders)
    - NSF Authorization, 1969
    - NSF, 1967-1970
    - NSF, 1970
    - Index to Legislative History of NSF, 1945-1950
      Oversize: see Box 42
    - Max Tishler speech on Government and Science, September 26, 1963
    - EQD Speech on Science and Public Policy, October 1, 1964
    - State Use of Science in Public Planning, June 16, 1965
    - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, 1966
    - Panel on Science and Technology, January 1967
    - Geo. Woods' Keynote Address, Panel on Science and Technology, January 23, 1968
    - Draft of Chapter of The Congress and Science Policy, Richard A. Carpenter, September 1968
    - McKlroy remarks (two speeches), 1970
    - National Science Policy Comm. Hearings and correspondence, 1970
    - Philip Handler on Toward a National Science Policy, July 1970
  - Patents
    - Hearings before subcommittee on Patents and Scientific Inventions, Property Rights in Inventions made under Federal Space Research Contracts, 1959
    - Patents file, 1959-1960
    - Background, 1959-1964
    - Patents file, 1961-1964
    - Patent Regulations, Committee on Science and Astronautics, 1959-1960
    - Legal compilation on Patents, Dept. of Navy, 1960 (Box 34)
    - Articles, clippings, speeches, 1960-1962
    - Patent Hearings, 1960-1962
    - Saline Water, Science and Astronautics Hearings, 1961
    - Federal Bar Journal, Winter 1961
    - Publications, Reports, etc., 1961-1962
    - Report of Subcommittee on Patents on Ownership of Inventions, April 5, 1962
    - Proceedings before NASA on Proposed Revisions to Patent Waiver Regulations, December 10, 1962
    - Articles, clippings, correspondence, press releases, 1962-1963
    - Correspondence, pamphlets, press releases, 1962-1963
    - Working Group, 1962-1963
    - EQD Speech -- Texas Manufacturers Assn., November 1962
    - EQD Speech-- Boston Patent Law Assn., February 1962
    - University Research and Patent Policies, Practices and Procedures, by Archie M. Palmer, 1962
    - Patent Statements, 1963
    - Articles, clippings, correspondence, notes, reports, speeches, 1963
    - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 35)
    - Patent Application - Solenoid Valve Mechanism, 1963-1964
    - Speech on Patent Policy, 1963
    - Shelton statement to Subcommittee on Patents, Trademarks and Copyrights, 1963
    - Bulletin, Rights in Data, April 1963
    - Statement on the Impact of Government Patent Policy, December 1963
    - Patent Advisory Panel Progress Report, June 1964
    - Federal Register, July 10 and August 27, 1964
      Includes Patent Waiver Regulations.
    - Clippings, articles, etc.
    - Policy developments, 1964
    - Water Resources Research Bill, 1964
    - Patent, Trademark & Copyright Information, 1965
    - Public Domain Policy, 1965
    - Patents Bill, views and opinions, 1962-1965
    - Patents Bill, drafts, 1963-1965
    - Air Pollution Control Bill, 1965
    - Transportation Bill, 1965
    - Water Pollution Bill, 1965
    - Health Research Facilities Act, 1965
    - McClellan Subcommittee
    - NASA Patents Statements
    - Appalachia File, 1965
    - Articles, general correspondence, 1965
    - Articles, clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, reports, 1965
    - Drafts, memoranda, reports, statements, 1965
    - Bills, correspondence, reports, 1965
      Oversize -- see Box 42.
    - Federal Bar Journal, Winter 1965
    - Hearings in the Subcommittee on Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights on Government Patent Policy, 1965
    - Articles, correspondence, drafts, memoranda, 1966 (Box 36)
    - Articles, correspondence, 1966
    - Articles, correspondence, drafts, pamphlets, memoranda, 1967
    - Articles, correspondence, 1967
    - Articles, correspondence, 1968-1970
    - Patent Policy Legislation, Volumes 1-6
      Index in Volume 1.
  - Research
    - Publications by Simon Marcson, 1959-1964
    - The Competition for Quality, Non-salary factors affecting the selection, recruitment, development, and retention of superior personnel in the scientific service of the Federal Government, Federal Council for Science and Technology, April 1962
    - Jerome B. Wiesner testimony, Science Subcommittee, October 1963
    - Edward Teller testimony, Science Subcommittee, October 18, 1963
    - Science, Education, and Politics, by Earl W. Lindveit, November 1963
    - Elliott Committee, 1963-1964
    - Panel notes, Technology and Science, Administrative Control, April 17, 1964
    - F. A. L. Holloway testimony, Science Subcommittee, May 28, 1964
    - General Motors statement, Science Subcommittee, June 1964
    - General Dynamics statement, Science Subcommittee, June 1, 1964
    - Testimony of Mr. Danhof of Brookings, Comptroller Shea of Univ. of Va., and Pres. Ellis, Univ. of Mo., Science Subcommittee, June 4, 1964
    - Courtlandt S. Gross and Dr. William E. Shoupp testimony, Science Subcommittee, June 4, 1964
    - Annual Report, Council of Scientific and Industrial Research, 1964-1965
    - Rensselaer application for Government funding
    - Biomedical Research - Italy (Grants from U.S.), 1966
    - Federal Laboratory hearings, 1967-1968
    - Research Management Advisory Panel, October 13, 1969
    - Federal Laboratories
    - Scientific Research Through International Cooperation, by E. Q. Daddario, report to Subcommittee on International Cooperation and Security
  - Science and Astronautics Committee (S & A) (Box 37)
    - Foreign travel, 1960
    - Notes by EQD on Hearings, 1963
    - Manned Space Flight, 1963, 1965
    - Statements before the Committee, 1963-1964
    - Charles Lindbergh, 1964
    - Committee File, 1965
    - Metric Study Bill, 1965
    - Notes by EQD on Hearing with Space Council, February 26, 1965
    - Articles, correspondence, memoranda, 1965
    - Correspondence, 1966
    - General releases to members of S&A Committee
    - Memoranda, press releases, reports, 1966
    - Statements before S&A Committee, 1967-1970
    - Committee Reports, 1968
    - California Trip, March 1969
    - Science, Research, and Development Subcommittee (SRD)
      - Articles, correspondence, memoranda, testimony, 1961-1965
      - Air Force and Space Digest, October 1963
      - United Aircraft Memorandum, 1963
      - Government-Science Forum, November 5-6, 1963
      - Articles, clippings, 1963
      - Articles, clippings, correspondence, statements, 1963-1965
      - SRD replies, 1963-1965
      - Appointments file, 1964
      - Science, August 28, 1964
      - Correspondence, memoranda, notes, press releases, 1965
      - Press releases, 1965
      - Recommendations of Subcommittee on SR&D, 1965
      - Mailing List, 1965
      - Correspondence, 1965
      - Indirect Costs, 1965-1968
      - Testimony before the committee (Box 38)
      - Second Progress Report of the SR&D, 1966
      - Articles, correspondence, 1968
      - Subcommittee replies, 1968
      - Correspondence, Letter to the President, 1969
      - Subcommittee replies, 1969
        Two folders.
      - Subcommittee replies, 1970
      - Summary of Activities of the SR&D Subcommittee from 1963-1970
  - Space